<blockquote>The power that local governments have over IT corporations is based on money. At any given moment, a government can crash their stocks by threatening to block revenue streams from its markets and thus force these companies to do strange things (remember how last year Apple moved iCloud servers to China).

At Telegram, we have the luxury of not caring about revenue streams or ad sales. <strong>Privacy is not for sale, and human rights should not be compromised out of fear or greed.</strong></blockquote>

使政府凌驾在互联网企业之上的权力，是建立在金钱利益之上的。政府随时都能威胁企业，把它们的主流服务拒之于本地市场之外，从而打击它们的股价，从而迫使它们做出一些奇怪的事情（还记得去年苹果是如何把 iCloud 服务器转移到中国的吧）。
 
而 Telegram 则有余裕不需担心收入来源或者广告收益。<strong>个人隐私不是用来出售的，人权也不应由于恐惧或贪婪而受到损害。</strong>

（自译）