-Riker: Do you remember how you've felt when Tasha died?
-Data: I do not sense the same feeling of absence that I associated with lieutenant Yar, although I cannot say precisely why.
-Riker: Just human nature, Data.
-Data: Human nature, sir?
-Riker: We feel the loss more intensely when it is a friend.
-Data: But should not the feeling run just as deep regardless who has died?
-Riker: May be they should, Data. May be if we felt every lose as kining* as we felt the death of one close to us, human's history will be lot less blooded.

-Troi: Children often feel that they must be true to the memory of the loss of parent. If you offer the affection too soon, they can feel guilty, returning that the affection. As if they are trained to love their parent.
-Worf: I only wish to honor his mother.
-Troi: I know, and I understand this means great due to you. But you must be prepared. He's very angry too, but he's angry deeply inside him. When you touch it, it will strike out to many directions, including yours. Be with him, talk to him, but don't rush him. When he's ready, he will know.

-Picard: I appreciate your motive, but, he's mother is dead. He must learn to live with that.
-"Aster": I will be every bit his mother.
-Picard: But it's not his mother.
......
-"Aster": Your philosophy is curious, captain. What is your so note about sorrow? I can provide him an existence where he will feel no pain, no anguish.
-Picard: It's the heart of nature to feel pain, and joy. It's the central part of make us what we are.
-"Aster": He's alone now in your world! A child! Alone! How can you know he won't be happy with me!
-Picard: For a bit of moment to time, he sure he would be, any others in his place would be.
......
-Picard: Do you honestly believe he would be happy in this total fiction? Which you wish to create? What's reason he has to live! What's your offer him is a memory, something to cherish, not to live in. It's part of life cycle that to be accept the death of those we love. Jeremy must come to turn what he's agreed and is not cover it! Or hide away from it! You see, we are mortal. Hard time in this university is finite. That's one of the truth all humans must learn.


From The Bonding, in the third season of TNG.